An evil old house , the kind some people call haunted ...
is like an undiscovered country waiting to be explored .
Hill House had stood for 90 years and might stand for 90 more .
Silence lay steadily against the wood and stone of Hill House .
Whatever walked there walked alone .
Scandal , murder , insanity , suicide .
The history of Hill House was ideal .
It had everything I wanted .
It was built 90-odd , very odd years ago ...
by a man named Hugh Crain as a home for his wife and daughter ...
in the most remote part of New England he could find .
It was an evil house from the beginning .
A house that was born bad .
Hugh Crain 's young wife ...
died seconds before she was to set eyes on the house .
She was killed when , for no apparent reason ...
the horses bolted , crashing her carriage against a big tree .
Mrs. Crain was carried ...
lifeless is the word , I think ...
into the home her husband had built for her .
Hugh Crain was left an embittered man ...
with a small daughter , Abigail , to bring up .
Fortunately , for me , that is ...
Hugh Crain did not leave Hill House . He married again .
The second Mrs. Crain 's death was even more interesting ...
than her predecessor 's .
I 've been unable to find out how or why she fell ...
although I have my suspicions .
Hugh Crain left Abigail with a nurse and went to England ...
where he died in a drowning accident .
Marvelous !
I mean , the way the history of Hill House follows a classic pattern .
For some reason ...
Abigail kept that same nursery room in Hill House where she grew up ...
and grew old .
In later years , she became a bedridden invalid .
She took a girl from the village to live with her as a paid companion .
It 's with this young companion ...
the evil reputation of Hill House really begins .
The story goes that the old lady died calling for help ...
in the nursery upstairs ...
while the companion fooled around with a farm hand on the verandah .
The companion inherited Hill House and occupied it for many years .
The local people believe that , one way or another ...
she had murdered her benefactor .
She lived a life of complete solitude in the empty house ...
though some say that the house was not empty ...
and never has been since the night old Miss Abby died .
They say that whatever there was and still is in the house ...
eventually drove the companion mad .
We do know she hanged herself .
After her death ...
the house passed legally into the hands of a distant relative in Boston ...
an old lady , Mrs. Sannerson , who I very much wanted to see .
All my life I 've been looking for an honestly haunted house .
In the interests of psychic research , you must let me have it for a few weeks .
No one who rented Hill House ever stayed for more than a few days .
The dead are not quiet in Hill House .
I don 't believe it .
Dr. Markway is a trained anthropologist ...
a respected member of a university faculty .
We should welcome such a man to investigate Hill House .
Perhaps .
As an old woman due shortly to enter the next world ...
I 'd like to know if there is one .
I 'm sure his report will give Hill House a clean bill of health .
How will you go about conducting your investigations , Dr. Markway ?
I shall occupy the house with a group of carefully selected assistants ...
- Assistants ? - My dear Mrs. Sannerson ...
I am a scientist conducting an unusual experiment .
A haunted house . Everyone laughs .
So I must have specially qualified help ...
to take notes and document any evidence of the supernatural I may find .
- Who are these assistants ? - I haven 't made my final choice yet ...
but they 're from a list of names I 've been assembling over the years .
- We don 't want any publicity seekers . - Of course not .
These people have only been selected after painstaking research .
They 've all been involved before , one way or another , with the abnormal .
I don 't like the sound of that .
- Are any of the people women ? - Some .
- Are you a married man ? - Yes .
Then your wife will be accompanying you .
I 'm afraid not .
My wife disapproves of my experiments with the supernatural .
She wants no part of Hill House .
To make sure that everything is as it should be ...
suppose your nephew goes along with Dr. Markway ?
Luke ?
Our young Lochinvar from out of the Midwest .
I haven 't much confidence in that branch of the family .
In this case , I think you can . Luke expects to inherit Hill House ...
and he 'll make sure that his property is well taken care of .
His property ?
Still , it might be rather good at that .
Luke hopes one day to live off Hill House .
But he never dreamed to find himself living in it .
Harper , give Dr. Markway his lease .
Thank you , Mrs. Sannerson .
A word of warning : Don 't play gin with Luke .
He 's a cardsharp .
Good . That indicates a strong instinct for self-preservation .
Exactly what do you and your assistants expect to find at Hill House ?
Maybe only a few loose floorboards , and maybe ...
I only say maybe ...
the key to another world .
You 've just got to let me have the car .
There 's no other way of getting there , and I 'm expected .
- Calm down . - I 've even bought some new clothes .
Please , Bud .
Carrie drives the car all the time and I never even take it out of the garage .
- Mother ... - Mother what ?
Nothing .
Auntie Nell is blinking .
Quiet , Dora .
Let 's talk this over without anybody getting emotional or nervous .
Why shouldn 't I be nervous ?
My first chance for a vacation in my life and you won 't let me take it .
There 's a good reason Mother was afraid for you to go anywhere ...
and it still applies .
We 're not going to dig up the family skeleton again , are we ?
I think you should have a vacation , Nell .
Nobody knows better than me what you went through during your mother 's illness .
Dirty laundry , the smell of that sickroom ...
Talk about mean old ladies !
Let the dead rest in peace .
It 's half my car . I helped pay for it and I mean to take it .
We don 't know where you 're going .
You haven 't seen fit to tell us anything , have you ?
No , you may not have the car .
What beats me is why you 're playing this thing so cozy ...
like this was a jailbreak .
In any case , I 'm sure I 'm doing what Mother would have thought best .
Although I don 't suppose poor Mother 's wishes mean much to you .
Get out . Get out , both of you .
Now just a minute , young lady . You happen to be in my living room .
I happen to be in my bedroom , and I pay a good part of your rent for it .
Now get out before I show you what my nerves can really do !
Besides , how do I know you 'll bring back my car in good condition ?
Come on .
I want my car . I mean to take it .
- Which ? - The Fredericks ' car .
- You ain 't Mrs. Fredericks . - It 's half mine .
- Who are you ? - Her sister , Miss Lance .
Look , here 's my driver 's license ...
here 's my library card ...
and here 's a blood donor card .
All the same address as my sister 's . I live with her .
- Front row , left of the far pillar . - Thank you .
" Very happy that you 'll be joining us in Hill House .
" Take US 50 from Boston ...
" and watch for the turnoff onto Route 238 . "
Route 238 .
At last I am going someplace where I 'm expected ...
and where I 'm being given shelter .
And I shall never have to come back .
I hope ...
This is what I 've been waiting for all my life .
I 'm going . I 'm really going .
I 've finally taken a step .
By now they know the car is gone ...
but they don 't know where .
They would never have suspected it of me .
I would never have suspected it of myself .
I 'm a new person .
Someday ...
Someday I 'll have an apartment of my own ...
in a house with a pair of stone lions guarding the gate .
I might just stop anywhere and never leave again .
Or I might drive on and on ...
until the wheels of the car are worn to nothing ...
and I 've come to the end of the world .
I wonder if all homeless people feel that way .
I wonder what Dr. Markway is like .
I wonder who else will be there .
I wonder what Hill House is like .
- What do you want ? - I want to come in , please .
- Please unlock the gates . - Who says ?
I 'm supposed to come in . I 'm expected .
- Who by ? - Dr. Markway .
- You better come back later . - Please .
I 'm one of Dr. Markway 's guests .
He 's expecting me in the house . Please listen to me .
He can 't rightly be expecting you ...
seeing as you 're the only one who 's come so far .
Do you mean that there 's no one in the house ?
No one you 'd want to see .
- What did you say your name was ? - Eleanor Lance ...
and I am expected in Hill House .
- Unlock those gates at once . - All right .
Suppose you know what you 're asking for coming here .
Suppose they told you , back in the city .
You seem to be the one who 's afraid .
You 'll be sorry I ever opened the gate .
Out of the way , please . You 've held me up long enough .
- Are you Dudley , the caretaker ? - I 'm Dudley , the caretaker .
I shall report you .
Think they can find anyone else to stay here ?
Think we can 't have things the way we want , me and the wife ...
as long as we stay around here , see to the house ...
for all you city people think you know everything ?
It 's staring at me .
Vile .
Get away from here . Get away at once .
It 's my chance . I 'm being given a last chance .
I could turn my car around and go away from here ...
and no one would blame me . Anyone has a right to run away .
But you are running away , Eleanor ...
and there 's nowhere else to go .
It 's waiting for me .
Evil , patient ...
waiting .
Mrs. Dudley ?
I 'm Eleanor Lance . I 'm expected .
Can you take me to my room ?
I gather I 'm the first one here , Mrs. Dudley .
You did say you were Mrs. Dudley ? I met your ...
Talk about being scared of your own shadow .
Pull yourself together .
Here .
This is your room .
How nice .
I can 't keep the rooms the way I 'd like ...
but there 's no one else they could get that would help me .
How very nice .
I set dinner on the dining room sideboard at 6 : 00 .
I clear up in the morning .
I have breakfast for you at 9 : 00 . I don 't wait on people .
I don 't stay after I set out the dinner .
Not after it begins to get dark .
I leave before the dark comes .
- Your husband ? - We live over in town , miles away .
So there won 't be anyone around if you need help .
I understand .
We couldn 't hear you ... in the night .
- Do you have any idea when ... - No one could .
No one lives any nearer than town .
No one will come any nearer than that ...
I know .
... in the night , in the dark .
I 'm like a small creature swallowed whole by a monster ...
and the monster feels my tiny movements inside .
Now , Eleanor Lance , you just stop it .
There 's no one else they could get . I set dinner on the ...
Thank heavens somebody 's here .
My name 's Eleanor Lance . I 'm so glad you 're here .
I 'm Theodora . Just Theodora .
What about this crazy house ?
I 'm right next door . We have a connecting bath .
This used to be the embalming room , I bet .
It was terrible being here alone .
I set dinner on the sideboard at 6 : 00 ...
Where 's Markway ? I thought he 'd be here first .
Serve yourselves . I clear up in the morning .
- Have you known Dr. Markway long ? - Breakfast is at 9 : 00 .
- I 've never met him . - I don 't stay after 6 : 00 , when it gets dark .
Our only contact is our correspondence about the " experiment . "
I leave before the dark comes .
So there won 't be anyone around if you need help .
No one can hear you if you scream in the night .
Isn 't that so , Mrs. Dudley ?
No one lives any nearer than town .
No one will come any nearer than that ...
in the night ... in the dark .
- You 're frightened , Nell . - No more .
Just when I thought I was all alone .
But how did you know my nickname is Nell ?
That is the affectionate term for Eleanor , isn 't it ?
Yes , I suppose it is .
What a nice way of putting it .
The affectionate term for Theodora is Theo .
We 're going to be great friends , Theo .
Like sisters ?
There 's no need to hang around our rooms .
- Let 's go exploring . - I 'd like to .
Why don 't you put on one of your new things ? Something that 'll stand out .
I think it 's a good idea around here to always remain strictly visible .
Be ready in a jiffy .
How did you know I brought new clothes ?
You wear your thoughts on your sleeve .
Anyway , that 's better than my heart .
How did I get into this ? Why am I here ?
What nightmares are waiting ?
Damn it ! I still say one of these doors should lead to the main hall .
Any lights near you , Nell ?
It helps if you make a game of it .
Pretend this is hide-and-seek .
But we 're still lost .
Yes .
That passageway . We haven 't tried that one yet .
What 's the matter ?
There 's something with us .
I don 't see anything .
- Can 't you feel it ? - No .
I feel a chill .
- It 's moving . - It 's just the air rushing past our ears .
Then who ?
What ?
The house , it 's alive .
She didn 't hear that .
Nobody heard it but me .
It wants you , Nell .
The house is calling you .
I 've waited such a long time . Is this what I came so far to find ?
Don 't let me go ! Theo , stay with me !
You won 't believe this , but five minutes ago I left this door open ...
so you could find your way . It closed by itself .
Welcome to Hill House . I 'm Dr. Markway .
Thank goodness . I thought you might be a ghost .
- How do you know I 'm not ? - Don 't be ghoulish .
You mustn 't confuse ghoulish and ghostly .
The word " ghoulish " is used to describe a feeling of horror ...
often accompanied by intense cold .
It has nothing to do with ghosts . Ghosts are visible .
- Enough of that . Get us out of here fast . - What 's the matter ?
Let 's just say we 're scared of the dark .
I , too , go in mortal terror of the dark .
- I 'm Theodora . - You must be Eleanor .
I 'm unsure at the moment .
If it turns out you 're not , I 'll be disappointed .
All right .
It 's Theo who 's wearing velvet , so I must be Eleanor in tweed .
Good .
Follow me through the uncharted waste of Hill House .
Dinner 's waiting .
- Do you like it ? - Lovely . What do you call this ?
The Purple Parlor .
We 're going to use this as the operating room .
I mean the center of operations .
- It 's not very cheerful . - I don 't know .
There 's nothing more cozy than an old gargoyle ...
except maybe a whipping post or two .
This house does have its little oddities .
The man who built it was a misfit ...
who hated people and their conventional ideas .
He built his house to suit his mind .
For instance , all the doors are hung slightly off-center .
Probably explains why they keep swinging shut by themselves .
Watch .
Now watch this .
What did I tell you ?
Anyway , all the angles are slightly off . There isn 't a square corner in the place .
No wonder it 's impossible to find your way around .
Add up all these wrong angles ...
and you get one big distortion in the house as a whole .
Clever , Eleanor . You catch on fast .
I 'm hungry .
Let 's go .
Sorry . In the psychic world we 're apt to forget ...
that food is still the main concern of poor old homo sapiens .
You see ? Closed by itself .
To the right , ladies .
Now , which door ?
- That one . - Wrong .
I 've studied a map , it 's this one .
- This proves it , one of you is a witch . - A broom closet .
If you can 't find your way around , how will we ever ?
All these doors , it makes me think of the lady and the tiger .
Let 's see if there 's a tiger behind this one .
That 's funny .
- No tiger ? - Listen .
What 's wrong ? Too much vermouth ?
Nothing that serious ...
and , please , no cracks about my passion for spirits .
If you two are the ghostly inhabitants of Hill House ...
I must confess I 'm glad I came .
It has taken 60 million years ...
to develop the carnivorous biped you see before you .
Luke Sannerson .
Let 's see what kind of martinis it makes .
They should be pretty good . I majored in them at college .
Are we to expect any more carnivorous bipeds ?
Originally , there were six committed to the experiment ...
but one by one the others dropped out .
I suppose they were frightened by the various unsavory stories about the house .
You 're the only ones left .
What stories ?
You didn 't investigate before you came here ?
So much the better .
You should be innocent and receptive .
- So let 's drink to our success . - Success ?
And just how do you reckon success in a junket like this ?
I 'd like to drink ...
to just us , good companions .
Excellent .
To my new companion .
Except I don 't drink .
- I think I 'll have some more salmon . - Palissy .
- Yeah ? How much is it worth ? - Plenty .
Haven 't seen Palissy outside of a museum .
I 'll take a pair of Kastle skis for them any day of the week .
I wonder how much I 'll get for this New England fossil .
Don 't let Mrs. Dudley hear you saying that . At the moment she 's giving us the best .
I 'm a simple fellow myself , easily satisfied by the best of everything .
Including , I hope , some startling events to come .
Exactly what do you expect to happen , Dr. Markway ?
Yes , what is the matter with Hill House ?
What 's going to happen ? Why are we here ?
Like so many people through the ages , I 've been intrigued by the supernatural ...
or rather the possibility of the supernatural .
I 'm here in hopes of proving its existence .
You 're here to keep track and take notes for an authenticated record .
- Okay . But why us ? - It 's no accident .
You 're what 's left of a select company chosen with great care .
I combed the records of psychic societies ...
the back numbers of newspapers , reports of parapsychologists ...
hoping to find people who 've been touched in some way by the supernatural .
It 's my belief that the very presence of people like yourselves in this house ...
will help to stimulate the strange forces at work here .
Charming thought , to be used as live bait .
I 'm here because I 'm a wolf in ghost 's clothing .
I 'm not really running a psychic beauty contest .
You 're here , Theo ...
because of your remarkable powers of extrasensory perception .
ESP ? Don 't believe in it .
Theo 's a champ .
Her name shines in the annals of Duke University Psychic Lab ...
where she identified 19 out of 20 cards ...
held up out of sight and hearing .
But I 've never had anything to do with the supernatural .
Yes , you have , Eleanor . Your poltergeist experience .
What 's a poltergeist ?
- A playful ghost , isn 't that right , Nell ? - I wouldn 't know .
According to the records of the International Psychic Society ...
showers of stones fell on your house for three days when you were 10 years old .
That 's ridiculous .
It was witnessed by your family ...
the neighbors , sightseers and the police .
In fact , it 's the only case ever officially recorded by the police .
It never happened .
Perhaps not , if you say so .
I only mention it because that 's the reason I wanted you in Hill House .
Doc , level with us .
I mean , you 're a college prof . A man with a PhD .
You can 't really believe there 's such a thing as a haunted house .
I wish you 'd stop referring to this desirable property as haunted .
There 's that word " haunted " again .
Makes me expect to find a disembodied hand in the sauce .
Nobody knows even why some houses are called haunted .
What would you call this place ? Fun-o-rama ?
Diseased , sick , crazy if you like .
A deranged house isn 't a bad way of putting it .
Your aunt thinks that maybe Hill House was born bad .
Such houses are described in the Bible as leprous .
Or before that , in Homer 's phrase for the underworld :
A house of Hades .
Come off it , Doc .
Really , the local mayor makes more sense to me .
He says the disturbances are caused by subterranean waters ...
electric currents , atmospheric pressure , sunspots , earth tremors , et cetera .
Sure , people always want to put an easy label on things ...
even if it 's meaningless .
" The trouble with Hill House is sunspots . "
There 's an explanation you don 't have to think twice about .
And it has a scientific ring .
That was the neighbors . They threw the rocks .
Mother says they were against us because she wouldn 't mix with them .
Mother says ...
Oh , dear .
That 's all right , Eleanor .
- Go on . What does your mother say ? - Nothing .
I must be more tired than I thought .
My mother died two months ago .
You weren 't sorry when it happened ...
were you ?
No , she wasn 't very happy .
Then I won 't say I 'm sorry now .
If I 'd known , I 'd never have asked you to come here .
But I 'm grateful you did . I had to get away .
- Perhaps you should ... - Please , let 's talk about something else .
Oh , dear .
Doc , see that ? Now what about that ?
Does salt work against the supernatural ?
The Montusi bushmen thought so , but they 're extinct .
You see , you haven 't a ghost of a chance .
I have a place in this room .
These people are my friends .
I 'm one of them . I belong .
Gin !
- That 's the fifth time , five times in a row . - $ 12 , please .
- I hope your skirt isn 't stained . - That 's all right .
But the upholstery on the couch .
I 've cleanser upstairs .
- Do you think I 'm a sucker ? - Pay up . Cash on the line .
Over my dead body . You knew every card I had in my hand .
- There 's a name for that . - If you mean cheating , I don 't have to .
Okay , Miss ESP , go dream yourself up the $ 12 .
Pay up , you welsher ! I won fair and I want my money .
- What was it ? - I had a feeling .
- I 'm sure it was just my imagination . - A feeling you were being watched ?
Yes , I did .
The house . It watches every move we make .
- That 's your imagination . - Don 't be so cocksure of everything .
A closed mind is the worst defense against the supernatural .
You think you 're too civilized to need to protect yourself against evil spirits .
But even prehistoric man had a dozen practical methods of warding them off .
Some of your theories strike me as prehistoric .
Besides , they downgrade property values .
I know the supernatural is something that isn 't supposed to happen .
Yet it does happen .
Ghosts make the papers along with celebrities every day of the week .
If it happens to you ...
you 're liable to have that shut door in your mind ...
ripped right off its hinges .
Look , Doc , we 're buddies , but don 't try to convert me .
I 'm trying to prepare you .
There 's something going on in this house or I wouldn 't be here .
What ?
Don 't ask me to give a name to something which hasn 't got a name .
I don 't know .
Tomorrow we 'll see all the place . Now let 's go to bed .
Unless anyone wants to clear out now ...
and not have anything more to do with Hill House .
I hope to have plenty to do with it someday , moneywise .
We couldn 't leave now even if we wanted to .
- You mean I 'm holding you prisoner ? - I mean Dudley keeps the gates locked .
We could always break out .
I have a key to the gate anytime you want it .
- I wouldn 't dream of leaving . - Thank you .
Adventurers all .
But you mustn 't expect every night to be Halloween .
Psychic phenomena are subject to certain laws .
And just what are these laws ?
You won 't know until you break them .
At the end of each day , you have to fill out these forms I 've had mimeographed .
Very scientific , aren 't we ?
The really scientific phase won 't start for a while yet .
First of all , we have to get orientated .
What 's this ? Looks like " psy-kookiness . "
Nothing like that wrong with me .
Psychokinesis is just the technical form ...
for what you 'd call objects moving by themselves .
Actually , they don 't ...
but are moved by a force from somewhere which we call psychokinesis .
I see .
About this ghost I can expect in my room tonight ...
tell me , is it male or female ?
Good night , ladies , Doc .
I just thought of something . Nobody locked the front door .
Won 't make any difference .
I see .
- Good night , Dr. Markway . - John .
Good night , Theo . Get a good rest , Eleanor . Sleep well .
I 'll turn the lights off below , in case you wonder who did it .
If you feel in the least bit nervous , just run right into my room .
Thanks . Good night .
I 'll come in for a second .
You 've been thinking of changing your hair . I know just the style for you .
Why , yes . I was . But I 'm awfully tired .
- Thanks anyhow . - Okay . We have a date for breakfast .
Good night , Theo .
Funny . Everything 's so ugly and yet so comfortable .
Like drowning , I guess .
Now I can think about them . I 'm all alone .
Alone .
He won 't know I locked it .
Against what , Eleanor ?
All right , Mother .
Just a minute . I 'm coming .
What , Theo ?
Nell , in here !
I 'm here . What is it ?
I thought it was you pounding .
It was . I mean , I did .
But now it 's down near the other end of the hall .
It 's not at all like Mother knocking on the wall .
It 's only a noise , and the room is terribly cold .
Terribly , terribly cold .
It must be Luke and Dr. Markway .
Why should they be knocking on the walls ?
Something is . Anyway , it 's only a noise .
Earth tremors ?
Maybe it 'll go down on the other side of the hall .
- No ! - Go away !
Now I 've done it .
It was looking for the room with someone inside .
You big baby .
Whatever it is , it 's just a noise .
- I 'm cold . - So am I.
- Where 's Luke ? Where 's Markway ? - I don 't know .
- Warmer now ? - No .
In a minute I 'll go out in the hall and call them .
Are you all right ?
Oh , God , Nell !
It 's against the top of the door !
It 's found us .
Now I know why people scream , because I think I 'm going to .
Is the door locked ?
You can 't get in !
It 's over .
- How do you know ? - Can 't you feel it ?
Aren 't you warm again ? That terrible cold has gone .
Why , yes .
Intense cold is one of the symptoms of shock . My mother ...
Intense shock is one of the symptoms I 've got .
Where have you two been ?
What 's the matter ? You look like you 've seen a ghost .
Did anything happen ?
Nothing in particular ...
just something knocked on the door with a cannonball ...
then tried to get in and eat us .
I 'm with Nell .
Miss ESP and Bridey Murphy , some combination .
- There isn 't a scratch on the wood . - Or anywhere else .
How nice , it didn 't mar the woodwork .
Where were you , Dr. Markway ?
Chasing a dog .
At least , we assumed it was a dog .
We followed it outside .
You mean it was inside ?
I thought I heard something run past my room .
I woke Luke . We went looking for it all over the house ...
and finally out in the garden .
But let 's face it , girls , we didn 't get very far from the house .
Then you must 've heard that ungodly noise .
No , there wasn 't a sound from the house .
At least , nothing audible to us .
- We 'd better take precautions . - Against what ?
When Luke and I are decoyed outside ...
and you two are bottled up inside ...
wouldn 't you say that something , somehow , is trying to separate us ?
Good morning , Dr. Markway .
'Morning , and please call me John .
- This curious life seems to agree with you . - Thank you .
- Tea or coffee ? - Tea , please .
How is it you look so pretty after last night ?
That was last night .
There may have been a little noise .
One has to expect that in these old houses .
I give up . I was sure you 'd be packed and on your way .
Not likely .
This is my first vacation in years and I 'm going to enjoy it .
That 's the point . You need a real vacation . This isn 't the place for one .
I mean to stay . Period .
Unless , of course , you want to get rid of me .
No , you mustn 't think that .
Till last night you were just a name on my list .
I scarcely know Eleanor Lance .
- She 's horrible . - No , you mustn 't make fun of me .
You 're sweet and pleasant and everyone likes you very much .
I want to know more about you .
I dislike lobster , crack my knuckles when I 'm nervous ...
save buttons , and sleep on my left side .
Why on the left side ?
I read someplace it wears the heart out quicker .
That 's a depressing thought .
For the past 11 years I 've been walled up alive on a desert island .
I thought you might be hiding some dark romantic secret in your past .
Romantic ?
I 've spent all my adult life taking care of my invalid mother ...
until she died .
No , it wasn 't romantic .
Now that you 're free at last , you shouldn 't be wasting your time in Hill House .
- It 's a mistake . - But it isn 't , don 't you see ?
The only thing that kept me going ...
was that someday I knew something would happen .
Something truly extraordinary , like Hill House .
Yes , it 's extraordinary .
What 'll you do when you get back ? Do you have a job ?
No job , nothing . I don 't know what I 'm going to do .
You wouldn 't send me back , would you ?
That depends on what happens .
We may all have to go back .
But I won 't give up easily .
How did you get so interested in the supernatural ?
I didn 't want to become what my father called a practical man .
I come from one of those respectable English families ...
that dragged all the Victorian virtues into the 20th century .
In a Gladstone bag , of course .
Everything had to be practical and conventional .
So my first reaction as a kid ...
was to choose something useless and unconventional . Like ghosts .
But you 're an anthropologist now .
When I refused to read law at Oxford as my father had ...
there was a terrific row .
I took off for America , without my Gladstone bag ...
and worked my way through college .
I decided on anthropology because it seemed ...
to be a short step from the study of dead souls ...
to the study of dead men and dead civilizations .
I 'm not very practical , either .
But it didn 't occur to me till I was hooked ...
that my combined knowledge of anthropology and psychic phenomena ...
had led me on to something very practical .
You see , if ghosts , which are pure spirit , come from man ...
then perhaps it 's possible some day to have individuals ...
whose spiritual caliber far surpasses anything humanity has yet known .
Human nature could certainly stand some improvements .
However , my idea remains pure theory ...
until somebody proves definitely the supernatural exists .
Anyway , that 's enough about me . Now tell me about last night .
Thank you .
I 've been trying to remember .
I can remember knowing I was frightened ...
but I can 't remember actually being frightened , or how I felt .
I think it 's because it was so unreal .
Still could be subterranean waters , you know .
I hope not . That wouldn 't be nearly so exciting .
Not good , this feeling of excitement .
It 's the first sign you 've fallen under the spell of the house .
Maybe it isn 't just the house .
Then what else ?
Let 's blame it on sunspots .
Well , it wasn 't sunspots last night .
If anyone gets hurt , it 's going to be your fault , Markway .
No ghost in all the long history of ghosts ever hurt anyone physically .
We weren 't in any actual danger at all , isn 't that right , John ?
No , not entirely .
Fear alone can do the damage to the victim .
Prehistoric man , for instance , could die of fright during an eclipse .
- Poor sap . - You mean poor homo sapiens .
A modern man can react with the same unreasoning terror ...
to a supernatural event .
Especially if he doesn 't believe that the supernatural exists .
I 've always been more afraid of being left alone or left out ...
than of things that go bump in the night .
What are you afraid of , Theo ?
Of knowing what I really want .
- Good morning , fellow earthlings . - Luke , what are you afraid of ?
What I just saw in the hall .
- Is there something ? - You mean you haven 't seen it ?
The show 's just getting good . Come on .
Right here .
It 's writing ?
Writing .
Chalk .
Or something like chalk .
- Can you read it ? - No .
What ?
No .
Wipe it off , please . It 's crazy .
Crazy is the word for it , all right .
- Get something and wipe it off , Luke . - But it 's crazy . Why ?
Why all the fuss ? It spelled her name right , didn 't it ?
- Those letters spelled out my name . - Take it easy .
It 's my name ! It belongs to me and something is using it .
Writing it and calling me with my own name !
- Just because your name ... - That 's it !
It knows my name , doesn 't it ?
- It knows my name ! - Simmer down , Nell .
It could have said any of us . It knows all our names .
Did you write it ? Please tell me . I won 't be angry or anything .
I just want to know so that ...
Maybe it was only for a joke to frighten me .
You know none of us wrote it , baby .
- She 's lying , I could swear she did it . - Easy .
I clear breakfast at 10 : 00 .
- Why should I write your name ? - I set lunch at 1 : 00 .
Because I didn 't wait to have breakfast with you .
- You 're way out . - You don 't know Theo as I 'm beginning to .
- I clear up at 10 : 00 . - Mrs. Dudley , please !
- No one blames you for being upset . - It 's 10 : 00 .
Why me ? Why should I be the one chosen ?
Maybe something in the house finds you a kindred spirit .
Maybe it thinks you have more understanding and sympathy than we do .
Maybe you wrote it yourself .
Sure , I 'm just the kind to want to see my name ...
- scribbled all over this foul house ! - It 's one way to attract attention , isn 't it ?
You think I like the idea I 'm the center of attention ?
Why are you all done up in that new hairstyle ?
- You were the one who suggested ... - That 's enough .
How dare you ?
Can 't you see Theo 's just trying to get a rise out of you ...
so you won 't be frightened anymore ?
I 'm sorry .
Take Eleanor to her room .
We 'll postpone the tour of the house .
Okay , but don 't forget . I don 't want to spend another night ...
wondering what 's over my head or underneath me .
You wouldn 't leave me behind , would you ?
No one will leave you behind .
Holy cow ! Mount Rushmore !
- It 's not there . I don 't believe it 's there . - How ?
I thought you 'd get a kick out of it .
It 's supposed to be St. Francis curing the lepers .
I 'd say it 's a family portrait .
A composite .
The tall , draped , masculine type ...
that 's old Hugh Crain ...
pointing out all the great treasures in this creepy house he built .
The dame on the end down there and this one must be his two wives .
His daughter , Abigail .
- Now the dog ... - The dog you were chasing last night .
Yeah , very good .
Now that one , she 's got to be the companion .
The one who 's supposed to have murdered Abigail .
No , that was much later . When Abigail was an old lady .
I wonder how this statue got here . It wasn 't on the original inventory .
Maybe I 'll break it up and sell it for tombstones .
The companion reminds me of you , Nell .
Oh , no !
She does at that .
A natural beauty , I 'd call her .
What does he think of me , really ?
Am I being a fool ?
Don 't let me know too surely what he thinks of me .
This could be a family portrait of us .
- Don 't be ridiculous . - You 're the companion .
I 'm Abigail , grown up .
And Markway could be old Hugh .
- Where do I fit in ? - The dog .
When are you going to show me your ESP ?
Keep your hands to yourself .
What 's going on ?
More than meets the eye .
You know , this wouldn 't be such a bad room without the statue .
Ideal for the zombies ' annual ball .
Why don 't you dance with Hugh ? I believe he has his eye on you .
- That 's not funny . - Don 't be chicken .
- Leave her alone . - I bet she doesn 't know how to dance .
I do , too .
Hugh Crain , will you dance with me ?
I believe he 's going to accept .
- He moved . - Of course .
Haven 't you noticed how nothing in the house moves till you look away ...
and then you just catch something out of the corner of your eye ?
She stepped on my toe .
Let 's go out this way before somebody gets hurt .
Come over here , I want to show you something really unique .
A library complete with ivory tower .
I can 't go in there .
- My mother ... - Yes ?
That smell ...
- It 's just stale air , Eleanor . - No , that other smell ... Awful .
Smells sweet to me , honey .
At 25 cents a book , I should do all right with this room .
I don 't think I 'll do much reading while I 'm here .
- Not if the books smell like the library . - I didn 't notice it .
No , that 's good , Eleanor . It 's just what we 're after .
Try and remember your reaction and describe it exactly ...
- when you write your notes tonight . - That 's what I 'm here for .
Only , do you mind if I skip the library for now ?
No , do just what you want . We 'll only be a minute .
- You 're sure you 're all right ? - Yes .
I want to show you something really interesting .
You remember that companion , the one that Abigail had ...
when she was an old lady ? See that little balcony ...
clear up at the top there , right up there in the shadows ?
That 's where the companion hanged herself .
- It would have been easier to jump . - Without a parachute ?
They say she tied the rope on to the railing and then ...
Thanks , we get it .
I just had a great idea .
You know what I 'll do with this room ? After I inherit the house , of course .
I 'll turn it into a nightclub .
Tear out these bookshelves and put a band in there .
Now comes the best part .
A line of beautiful chorus girls dancing down these stairs .
Can 't you see it ?
- Are you all right ? - I think so .
- Quick thinking . - Instinct .
My strong instinct for self-preservation .
And it 's telling me right now loud and clear to get the hell out of here .
Vile . Hideous .
I wonder what it would be like looking down from there .
That 's where she did it .
From that window .
Climbing out through the bars ...
hanging on for an instant , hanging on ...
Eleanor , you 'll fall !
Didn 't you hear me calling ?
This house , you have to watch it every minute .
I didn 't realize you were so nervous . I think I should send you home .
- No , please , I can 't go home . - It 's no reflection on you .
An atmosphere like this might break anyone down .
But I 'm not breaking down .
I did hear noises last night .
Something was trying to get into the room .
You realize that if even one event is proved to be a hallucination ...
then this whole experiment will be questioned .
I 'm not crazy , you know .
After all , Theo was there , too . Is it my fault it just didn 't make sense ?
We 'll let it go for now .
- Maybe I 'm just being selfish . - Selfish ?
Keeping you here for the sake of the experiment .
Of course , for the sake of the experiment .
You do seem to be the main attraction ...
for whatever 's in the house .
- But I 'll send you back the minute ... - No , please . I 'm all right . Really I am .
Well , don 't you two look cozy .
She was halfway off the verandah when I caught her .
I was leaning back to see the top of the tower .
- I got dizzy . - Dizzy like a fox ?
Poor Nell .
You look like death . Let 's go inside .
I think you 'd better move in with Eleanor .
- You 're the doctor . - But that 's my room , my very own room .
I wouldn 't want to risk either of you spending another night alone .
Don 't get all hung up , Nell .
We 'll have fun . Like sisters .
- It tickles . - Of course .
Your toes are tickled pink .
I knew my shade would suit you perfectly .
Have another drink . It will keep the chill out .
Just a teensy one . To keep the chill out .
- I don 't really like whisky . - This is brandy .
By the time I 'm through with you , Nell , you 'll be a different person .
It 's wicked .
I mean , on my foot .
You 've got foolishness and wickedness mixed up .
Maybe .
Haven 't had much chance to learn the difference .
Know something ? Even when I 'd play solitaire in my room ...
she 'd bang on the wall and make me feel guilty ...
for leaving her alone just that little bit .
- She 'd always ... - Your mother ?
My mother ...
Story of my dull life .
What 's your apartment like ?
It 's an old place we furnished ourselves from stuff we picked up in the junk shops .
We both love fixing over old things .
Like me .
You married ?
No .
I 'm sorry .
I 'm stupid and wicked and untrustworthy ...
- and not good for anything at all . - I don 't think so .
Maybe just a little tight at the moment .
Tell me something about where you live .
I haven 't had it long enough to believe it 's my own .
It 's a little apartment . Smaller than yours , I 'm sure .
I live alone . I 'm still furnishing it .
Buying one thing at a time to make sure I get everything right .
Took me two weeks to find the little stone lions I keep on the mantel .
Brush their teeth every night .
I 've got a hunch I better get you back to your apartment as fast as I can .
- Don 't say that . - I only mean ...
Why do you all pick on me ?
Am I the public dump or something for everybody 's fear ?
I don 't want to leave Hill House ever .
I 've been waiting all my life for something like this to happen .
Hey , everybody , come here . I 've found something .
What 's wrong with you , Doc ?
Stand there , go on . You , too , girls . Stand there .
A genuine cold spot .
I guarantee it won 't register on any thermometer .
Bunk . It 's just a draft , that 's all .
- Coming from somewhere . - A draft ? In Hill House ?
Not unless you can make one of the doors stay open .
No , I found it . The heart of Hill House .
You mean where we 're standing ?
Behind these doors .
- What 's in there ? - The nursery .
Abigail Crain grew up and died there .
- Just the place to chill our beer . - No , don 't go in there .
We 'll keep the lid on the pressure cooker a while longer , then .
Now don 't give me that , Doc .
It 's like the doorway to a tomb .
Bless you .
Now , that 's enough , girls .
You 'd better run along to bed before you catch cold .
Yes , teacher . Bless you .
Come on .
No . There 's got to be a draft .
The floor 's solid .
Look , Doc , don 't give me any of that supernatural jazz .
This is something I can feel . And see .
Maybe there 's a pipeline to the North Pole .
Why won 't you accept it for what it is : A supernatural phenomenon ?
You knock on wood , don 't you ?
Yeah , what 's that got to do with it ?
It shows that even you , despite yourself ...
feel that there are forces beyond nature able to help or hurt us .
Wait a minute .
Are you telling me that belief in a superstition ...
is the same thing as believing in the supernatural ?
It 's food for thought .
Frozen food for thought .
You know what I think ?
Markway has us all so edgy , we 're getting the cold sweats .
The temperature needn 't drop to make you feel like that .
That 's right .
Music gives me goose bumps .
Still , there was that awful smell in the library .
Here we go again . You know very well ...
what you thought you smelled in the library . The sickroom smell .
Let 's discuss me some other time .
I 'm tired .
- Turn out the light . - I 'd like it on . Have you seen this ?
I told you . I just want to go to sleep . Good night !
Why be mad at me ? I don 't think you killed your mother .
Leave me alone .
Go to sleep !
Good night , Nellie my Nell .
Are you awake ? Don 't say a word , Theo . Not a word .
Don 't let it know you 're in my room .
Hold my hand .
And for God 's sake , don 't scream .
Is it over ? Do you think it 's over ?
You 're breaking my hand .
This is monstrous . This is cruel .
It is hurting a child and I will not let anyone ...
anything hurt a child .
I won 't endure this . It thinks to scare me .
It has , and poor Theo , too .
Honestly , it feels like she 's breaking my hand .
I will take a lot from this filthy house for his sake ...
but I will not go along with hurting a child . No , I will not .
I will get my mouth to open right now , and I will yell .
Stop it !
What , Nell ?
Oh , God !
Whose hand was I holding ?
- Eleanor , too bad . You just missed it . - What ?
The Hill House Concerto for Harp .
Were you playing the harp ?
It was playing itself .
Naturally . How do you explain it ?
Subterranean waters ? Earth tremors ?
As a matter of fact , I don 't think it is anything supernatural .
The self-starting music .
More likely it 's in the realm of the preternatural .
Something we don 't have any natural explanation for right now ...
but probably will have some day .
The preternatural of one generation becomes the natural of the next .
Not so long ago , scientists laughed at the idea of magnetic attraction .
They couldn 't explain it , so they refused to admit it existed .
Life is still full of the preternatural .
My mother ...
Go on . Say it . You 've been trying to since you got here .
I don 't know what I was going to say . I 'm still so terrified from last night .
You shouldn 't be . It 's silly to be frightened .
You haven 't been through it .
This horrible unknown thing .
Unknown . That 's the key word .
When we get involved in a supernatural event ...
we 're scared out of our wits just because it 's unknown .
The night cry of a child .
Face on the wall , knockings , bangings .
What 's there to be afraid of ?
You weren 't threatened . It was harmless , like a joke that didn 't come off .
- But the child ... - There was no child .
- Just a voice . - Worse .
Look , let me put it this way .
When people believed the Earth was flat ...
the idea of a round world scared them silly .
Then they found out how the round world works .
It 's the same with the world of the supernatural .
Until we know how it works ...
we 'll continue to carry around this unnecessary burden of fear .
Supposing it is in my imagination ...
the knocking , the voices , everything .
Every cursed bit of the haunting .
Suppose the haunting is all in my mind .
You can 't say that because there are three other people here .
We all resist the idea ...
that what ran through the garden the first night was a ghost ...
what banged on the door was a ghost , what held your hand was a ghost .
But there 's certainly something going on in Hill House .
We 're getting close , Eleanor , very close to finding out what it is .
I could say all three of you are in my imagination . None of this is real .
Sure . That 's the easiest way to dismiss the supernatural ...
by pleading insanity or accusing others of it .
Maybe I am insane .
The night my mother died ...
she knocked on the wall .
And I didn 't come .
Eleven years of looking in on her after every small noise .
That night ...
my back hurt and my hands .
It wasn 't fair . We could 've afforded a laundress .
I ought to have brought her the medicine . I always did before .
This time ...
she called me ...
and I never answered .
- Is that how a normal person acts ? - Yes .
You were tired and disgusted . 11 years !
You 're human .
Stop trying to be either a saint or a martyr .
You probably like thinking it was your fault .
My sister says I wanted Mother to die .
I 've wondered ever since if I didn 't wake up in the night ...
and hear her just go back to sleep .
It would have been easy .
- I 've wondered about it . - No , you 're not capable of that .
You 're a fine person , Eleanor .
Sensitive and honest and thoroughly good .
- Do you really think so , John ? - I do indeed .
Goose bumps .
There isn 't by any chance a cold spot in this room , too , is there ?
No , there isn 't .
" Journeys end in lovers meeting . "
All I want is to be cherished .
And here we are listening to that ridiculous harp .
" Lust . Daughter , preserve thyself .
" Hold apart from this world , that its lust corrupt thee not .
" Could you but hear for a moment the agony ...
" the screaming ... "
Oh , now , get this , congregation .
" ... the dreadful crying out of the lustful ...
" damned for eternity in everlasting flame ! "
- What have you got there ? - I found it in the library .
He made it himself .
Look .
" Memories for Abigail Lester Crain :
" A legacy for her education and enlightenment .
" From her devoted father , Hugh Desmond Lester Crain ...
" Hill House , October 21 , 1873 . "
- But that 's today . - Tomorrow and 90 years later .
Some nursery book , huh ?
" Honor the authors of thy being , daughter .
" Thy father and thy mother . "
Just the thing to give a child at bedtime . No family should be without one .
I can see him now spitting out the words so they take root in her little mind .
Hugh Crain , you were a dirty man and you made a dirty house .
If you can hear me , I 'm telling you to your face ...
I hope you spend eternity in that foul , rotten book ...
and never stop burning for a minute .
- Don 't be a bore , Nell . Sit down and we 'll ... - Leave me alone .
You are a bore .
I 've got it . I 'll tear out the pictures ...
and send them as Christmas cards to my New England relatives .
I think it 's funny . " Dear Uncle Ned : Merry Christmas , may your soul ... "
Close that book .
It 's enough to set anyone 's nerves on edge .
It 's not the book that 's making our Nell nervous .
She 's worried about her apartment .
I didn 't know . Is there anything I can do to help ?
She thinks she 's being funny .
Tell me , Dr. Markway , are you fond of stone lions ...
- the kind you keep on the mantel ? - Shut up , Theo .
Do you long for a tiny home , something smaller than Hill House ?
There 's room for two , isn 't there , Nell ?
You 're a monster , Theo . You 're the monster of Hill House .
- You 'd better go with her . - Wouldn 't you rather ?
I said go with her . She shouldn 't be left in that room alone .
Here you are . Okay , Isolde .
- Tristan wants you inside . - Leave me alone .
Stop trying to be the center of attention .
- Come inside . - You revolt me .
Can 't you take a joke ?
I didn 't know you were serious about Markway .
Of course you did .
But he shouldn 't be allowed to get away with it .
Get away with what ?
- You 're making a fool of yourself over him . - Suppose I 'm not , though .
You 'd mind terribly if you turned out to be wrong for once .
- You poor stupid innocent . - I 'd rather be innocent than like you .
Meaning what ?
Now who 's being stupid and innocent ?
- You know perfectly well what I mean . - Is this one of your crazy hallucinations ?
- I 'm not crazy . - Crazy as a loon .
You expect me to believe you 're sane and the rest of the world is mad ?
Why not ?
The world is full of inconsistencies .
Unnatural things . " Nature 's mistakes , " they 're called . You , for instance .
A reporter 's been telephoning all day . He 's on your track .
- He 's heard about you renting this place . - How ?
The Dudleys , I bet . They must 've blabbed in town .
Come back with me now , please .
If they find out why you 're here , the papers 'll have a field day .
Who are you ?
Grace Markway .
Didn 't John tell you he 's married ?
- I tried to warn you . - Welcome to our party .
Who are you ?
We 're researchers in the field of psychic phenomena .
Please go . You couldn 't have arrived at a worse time .
Stop this insanity , John , and come back with me .
I can 't . Not now .
I 'm convinced we 're on the verge of a breakthrough .
Here you are , driver , that 'll be all .
But I had to come . I had to .
I 've waited such a long time .
I 've earned my happiness .
I was afraid this would be your attitude .
I 'm not leaving here until you 've got sense enough to leave with me .
I hope no one minds if I join the ghost hunt .
All right , I 'll put your things in my room .
I 'll be very disappointed if I don 't see a ghost .
Hadn 't you better put me in the ghastly dungeon ...
or the mysterious secret chamber ?
There are no dungeons , no secret chambers in Hill House .
In fact , nothing romantic at all .
It 's a deadly serious place .
- Not even a treasure buried in the cellar ? - There 's the nursery .
Thank you , my dear . The nursery it is .
You must listen to me . Certain things have happened here .
You may not believe in the supernatural , but these are physical facts .
Mrs. Markway , please ...
Don 't sleep in the nursery .
I didn 't realize what I was saying .
You insult my intelligence .
You don 't think I 'd believe anything you ghost hunters might tell me .
Even so , you shouldn 't sleep in that room .
It hasn 't been opened since we 've been here .
I agree with you about the spook bit , Mrs. M , but it 's true , the air might be bad .
Oh , poisonous .
I 've just remembered . No problem .
I don 't have the key to the nursery , and the Dudleys have gone for the night .
Incidentally , how 'd you get through the gate ?
Very supernatural . With a key .
Your Mrs. Dudley is quite human , I assure you ...
and not at all averse to a $ 5 bill .
Hey , look .
From your expressions , I gather that is the dreaded nursery .
And as for the bad air , it 's quite the opposite .
There seems to be a draft .
Wait a minute , Doc .
This is ridiculous . Nobody opened these doors .
That 's right , Luke . You 're beginning to see the light .
I haven 't seen a damn thing .
I just don 't like the way it looks .
Now I know who your fiend of Hill House is .
The interior decorator .
Evidently Mrs. Dudley doesn 't get in here very often .
Looks the same as the rest of the house to me .
It 's no use , Grace . The air in here is stale .
I can take care of that .
Only one way to argue with a woman , Doc . Don 't .
Good night .
My mother ...
This room is the cold , rotten heart of the house .
Since you 're so foolish , I 'll stay with you .
But you 're not to be in this room alone tonight .
I can 't go on watching you waste your life on all this nonsense .
If there is such a thing as a haunted house , this is my chance to find out .
All right .
John , my bag .
At least leave the door open .
Don 't worry . I 've brought a special ghost trap with me .
What if he does have a wife ? I still have a place in this house .
I belong . I want to stay here .
It 's the only time anything 's ever happened to me .
He can 't make me leave , not if Hill House means me to stay .
Go away , Eleanor , we don 't want you anymore , you can 't stay .
But I can .
He doesn 't make the rules around here .
Nell , I 'm talking to you .
- I 'm sorry . - What 's the matter ?
Didn 't you hear Markway ?
He doesn 't want us to stay here .
He wants us to spend the night downstairs in the parlor .
Luke and he will take turns watching on this floor .
For Pete 's sake , snap out of it .
- Why aren 't you upstairs ? - I needed a drink .
- Grace . - Wait a minute .
It 's nowhere near the nursery , it 's down here .
It seems to me we 've been on this kick before .
Next vacation I must really go somewhere else .
It knows my name . This time it knows my name .
- I 'll have to go out there . - No !
- It hasn 't hurt me . Why should it hurt her ? - She might try to do something about it .
Is it over , Theo ? Is it ?
No , I 'm so cold .
It 's going to start everything all over again .
It can 't get in . Don 't let it get in .
Oh , God , it knows I 'm here .
Doc , I 'll let you have the house cheap .
It will go on and on and come back again until it finds me .
On and on until it finds me .
It 's at the nursery .
- You must be crazy ! - I 'm going out there !
Not with that thing out there .
- We have to , Luke . She 's there ! - Don 't be crazy .
I 've got to find out if Grace is all right .
I don 't know what it is , but I don 't want to find out ...
I 've got to get out of here . I 've got to find out if Grace is all right .
- No , don 't . - Cut it out !
I 'll come .
Whatever it wants of me it can have .
The house is coming down around me .
The house is destroying itself .
It 's in the nursery .
Mrs. Markway ?
Please .
Grace , are you ...
Where is she ?
- Where is she ? What did you see ? - Nothing .
She wasn 't here .
- What happened ? - She 's gone .
Where ? How ?
Good God !
Markway , if this is your idea of a joke ...
if living in a haunted house has done this to you ...
We 'll start here , then the whole house .
- Even if we have to tear the place apart . - You can 't do that .
If we don 't find her , the police will be around .
I 'm coming apart , a little at a time .
Now I know where I 'm going .
I 'm disappearing inch by inch into this house .
We killed her . You and I , Hugh Crain .
She must be around this house somewhere .
Maybe this whole thing is a bad joke .
- She isn 't the kind who makes jokes . - You find her , she 's your wife .
I 'm taking Nell and I 'm clearing out of here .
Where is Eleanor ?
I want to stay here .
I want to stay here always .
I will not be frightened or alone anymore .
Has anyone checked outside ?
Please , Nell , where are you ?
Here I am , inside .
It 's not cold at all and the smell is gone .
I 've broken the spell of Hill House .
I 'm home .
No stone lions for me . I am home .
I will not look back ...
because then they will know what I am thinking .
Eleanor , turn around and come down .
Now , be very , very careful .
Come down .
All that is gone and left behind .
Eleanor , for God 's sake !
- Wait a minute . This thing will collapse ... - It can 't possibly hold the both of you .
Just turn around , Eleanor .
Keep hold of the rail and start down slowly .
Stand still ! Don 't move !
Stand perfectly still !
Nell , do what they say , please !
I 'm coming on the platform .
Now come along .
Are you sure , Eleanor ?
It was Mrs. Markway .
Just before I fainted , I looked up , and there she was above the trap door .
What 's more , she 's still around .
I don 't know who or what you really saw , Eleanor .
But whatever it was , we can 't risk letting it happen again .
- That 's why you 're leaving now . - But I can 't leave now .
- I brought the car round front . She ready ? - She 's all packed . Take her suitcase .
No , please , Luke , let me stay .
I 'll help Mrs. Dudley .
All it will cost you is just my keep .
Sorry , honey , but you 're not the type I keep .
- I can 't leave , I tell you . - I can 't take any more chances .
I realize now what a terrible thing I was asking of you all .
You 're leaving as quickly as you can . Then we 'll find Grace or go to the police .
It isn 't fair .
I 'm the one who 's supposed to stay here . She 's taken my place .
Don 't worry . Luke will see you get there safely .
- Get where ? - Why , home , of course .
Go back to your own little apartment where all your things are .
I haven 't any home .
I made it up .
No apartment , no things ...
Everything in all the world that belongs to me ...
is in that suitcase and a carton in my car .
So you see , there 's no place you can send me .
I have to stay here .
You must have lived somewhere before .
- You had an address where I wrote you . - My sister 's .
I sleep on a couch in the living room .
I 'd be much happier here . I can 't go back to my sister 's .
Yes , you can , and immediately .
This is a mistake . Don 't you understand ? The house wants me .
Mrs. Markway can 't satisfy it . No one else can .
Forget about this house as soon as you can .
No , please . I 'm fine now . I 'm not afraid .
I was happy here .
- I don 't think Mrs. Markway will be . - Put the bag in the car , Luke .
Nell is right . Grace is around somewhere .
- You see ? - Please , there 's no time to waste .
Please , let me stay . I 'm the only one who can call Mrs. Markway back .
I was wrong . I should have sent you home the first night .
This is the only time anything 's ever happened to me .
I 'm the one it really wants .
Can 't you feel it ? It 's alive .
Watching ...
waiting ...
Waiting for me .
I won 't go away .
You will go away . Right now .
- No , come on . - I 'll drive . It 's my car .
At least , half mine .
All right , let her . I can 't stand here arguing .
Thank you for rescuing me in the library .
That was wrong of me , I know , but I 'm all right now , honestly .
I 'm sorry . I 'm terribly sorry , really .
Goodbye .
Let 's get moving .
I thought you weren 't going to say goodbye .
Nellie my Nell , be happy , please be happy .
Everything 's going to be all right .
I 'm sure Grace is here and we 'll find her . So don 't worry .
She has my place . It isn 't fair .
Goodbye , Eleanor .
I 'll write you . Drive carefully .
Goodbye .
Who do I thank for a lovely time ?
Oh , hold it . Markway !
The key .
- To the gate . - Yes , of course .
What fools they are . The house tricks them so easily .
Just by telling me to go away , they can 't make me leave .
They can 't shut me out .
Not if Hill House means me to stay .
- Eleanor . - Wait .
So now I 'm going .
But I won 't go . Hill House belongs to me .
I knew it .
Hill House doesn 't want me to go .
Stop it . Please . What are you doing ?
Let go .
What are you doing ?
Why don 't they stop me ? Can 't they see what is happening ?
But it 's happening to you , Eleanor .
Yes . Something at last is really ...
really happening to me .
She 's dead .
I didn 't want any of this to happen . You must believe me , John .
What were you doing ? What happened ?
That terrible house .
I woke up and I was frightened . So I tried to find your room , but I got lost .
Almost as though the house were doing it on purpose .
And I ended up in the attic .
I was only trying to find a way out when I opened the trap door .
I wasn 't trying to frighten her .
- Didn 't you see me ? - No , but Eleanor did .
The shock of seeing you almost killed her .
She did kill her .
Seeing her is what made Eleanor lose control of the car .
No . She only saw me the very last instant .
The same time I saw her .
I don 't even know how I got out here .
It wasn 't your fault .
Eleanor did it to herself .
It looked to me , anyway , like she ...
deliberately aimed the car at this tree .
Where the first Mrs. Crain was also killed in an " accident . "
Here 's the mark .
There was something in the car with her , I 'm sure of it .
Call it what you like , but Hill House is haunted .
It didn 't want her to leave , and her poor bedeviled mind ...
wasn 't strong enough to fight it .
- Poor Eleanor . - Maybe not " poor " Eleanor .
It was what she wanted , to stay here .
She had no place else to go .
The house belongs to her now , too .
Maybe she 's happier .
You wait here , Grace .
I 'll go and get your things and call the police .
No one must go in that house again . Whatever is there might ...
I 'll be all right .
The house has what it wants ... for a while .
It ought to be burned down and the ground sowed with salt .
Hill House has stood for 90 years and might stand for 90 more .
Within , walls continue upright , bricks meet ...
floors are firm , and doors are sensibly shut .
Silence lies steadily against the wood and stone of Hill House .
And we who walk here walk alone .